[ Music ]
[ 音乐 ]
[ Applause ]
[ 掌声 ]
&gt;&gt; Hi everyone.
&gt;&gt; 大家好
Welcome to the Introduction to
欢迎大家来到
Dark Mode session.
深色模式的介绍讨论会
My name is Raymond Sepulveda,
我叫 Raymond Sepulveda
and I'm a macOS designer on the
我是人机界面设计团队的
Human Interface Design team.
macOS 设计师
For the first half of today's
今天讨论会的前半部分
session, I'm going to be going
我将会介绍
over some of the design
一些设计理念
principles that went into the
这些理念
design of Dark Mode, as well as
都和深色模式有关
some of the design
还有一些
considerations that you should
设计的注意事项
take into account when updating
这些是你在更新软件
your own applications to take
适配深色模式时
advantage of Dark Mode.
需要注意的事项
Then, for the second half of the
然后在后半部分
session, my engineering
我工程领域的同事
colleagues Rachel Goldeen and
Rachel Goldeen
Taylor Kelly from the Cocoa
和来自 Cocoa 框架团队的 Taylor Kelly
Frameworks team are going to be
将会介绍
going over how to adopt and
如何采用
support Dark Mode using an
和支持深色模式
example application that they
他们会用一个 App 当作例子
built together.
这个 App 是他们一起设计的
The three of us are super
我们三个非常激动
excited to share all of these
可以向大家介绍
details with all of you, so
这些细节
let's jump right in.
我们现在就开始吧
As we announced in yesterday's
我们在昨天 Keynote 中已经提到了
keynote, macOS 10.14 is going to
macOS 10.14 将会有
be getting a new interface
一个全新的界面外观
appearance, and we call it Dark
我们称之为深色模式
The new design is very
这项新设计
attractive and engaging, while
非常吸引人
at the same time being very calm
同时又非常沉静而低调
These are great qualities for an
这些是一个界面
interface, and they make it
非常好的特质
great for creative professionals
对处理创作工作的专业人士很有帮助
who are dealing with heavily
当他们在处理非常细致的图像
detailed images and colorful
和彩色资源
assets such as images and video
比如说图像和视频资源时
But, in actuality, it's actually
但是 在实际使用中
great for just about any type of
深色模式适合每个
user who is looking to
想要集中精神
concentrate or focus on any
完成手头任务的用户
So, whether you're trying to
所以 无论你是想
concentrate on writing the next
专注地写一部精彩的小说
great novel or you're trying to
还是你想要
read one without disturbing your
读一部小说
bedside partner, Dark Mode is
而又不想打扰你的枕边人
really great for either type of
这两种情况都很适合
situation.
使用深色模式
The interface shares a lot of
深色模式和浅色模式
family resemblances between the
的交互界面之间
light appearance and the dark
有很多相同点
we wanted to encourage users to
这是因为我们想要鼓励用户
switch between both appearances
在这两种模式之间自由变换
easily and find the one that
并且找出其中
really best suits their needs.
符合自己需求的模式
And so it was very important
所以保持某些东西
that things like control
在两种模式之间
metrics, window layout, and the
尽可能相同
distribution of translucent
就十分重要 比如
materials be the same as much as
控件指标
possible between both
窗口布局
appearances.
和半透明素材的分布
As such it's also equally
同样重要的是
important that all of your
你的所有 App 软件
applications take full advantage
都应该充分应用这两种模式
of both appearances so that they
这样 不论是在
update correctly between both
什么系统下运行
appearances no matter what the
它们都可以
system is running under.
正确地更新
You really don't want to be that
你绝对不希望
one light appearance that's
某个浅色页面
stuck in dark appearance.
卡在深色页面上
All in all, we're super happy
总而言之 我们对这个
with how the design turned out,
设计成果非常满意
and we are really anxious to see
我们迫切想要看到
what you guys are going to turn
当你们拿到开发者 Beta 版时
your apps into as soon as you
你们会把 App
get hands on the developer beta
变成什么样子
and start adopting the Dark
并且开始采用
Mode.
深色模式
Aside from Dark Mode, another
除了深色模式
new interface feature that we
macOS 10.14 还有一个
added into macOS 10.14 are
新的界面特色
accent colors.
那就是强调色
Previous releases of macOS
macOS 之前的版本
offered two accent colors, blue
提供了两种强调色
and graphite, but for macOS
蓝色和石墨色
10.14, we've expanded the color
但是在 macOS 10.14 中我们增加了配色
palette to include eight fun
使它包含 8 种有趣的颜色
colors to really help you
可以真正帮助你
personalize your Mac.
个性化你的 Mac
So, if you're like me and you
所以如果你也像我一样
love the color red, you're going
喜欢我的发色
to immediately switch over to
你可以立刻把它切换成
the color red [laughs].
红色 [ 笑声 ]
If orange or yellow are more of
如果你更喜欢橘色或者黄色
your preference, you're going to
你也可以
switch over to those, and we
切换成这两种颜色
make those available as well.
它们现在也已经可用了
I should note that the accent
我需要强调的是
colors are not just a
强调色不仅仅是
sub-feature of Dark Mode, but
深色模式下的附加特色
they're also available in Light
在浅色模式下也同样适用
Mode.
所以如果你更喜欢浅色模式
want green accent color, you can
而且又想用绿色的强调色
do that as well.
你也可以这样做
So, now that we've covered a
现在 我们已经介绍过了
little bit of the basics of what
一点基础知识
Dark Mode is and what accent
包括深色模式
colors are also, let's dive a
和强调色是什么
little bit deeper into some of
现在让我们稍微深入地了解一下
the design principles that went
深色模式的设计理念
At Apple, when we begin a new
在 Apple 当我们开始一个
design project, we like to
新的设计项目时
establish a set of design
我们会设立一些
principles to help guide us
设计理念
throughout the entire design
在整个的设计过程中
process.
帮助指导我们
And, with Dark Mode, there were
对于深色模式来说
three in particular that we
有三个设计理念
referred to quite often
在整个设计过程中
throughout the entire process.
我们经常提起第一个
straightforward, so let's just
也是最直接的一个
jump right into that one, and
让我们直接跳到这一个
that is that dark interfaces are
那就是深色模式
cool, period, right?
很酷 就是很酷 没别的
They are almost effortlessly
它很轻易地就做到了
cool in a way that light
很酷这一点
interfaces sometimes kind of
而浅色模式
struggle to be.
有时很难显得很酷
But why is that, really?
但是这是为什么呢
Part of it is because we all
一部分原因是
have these notions of what a
我们对于深色模式是什么
dark interface is and what a
和它是什么样子的有概念
And a lot of that is fed into us
这些概念都是我们
by what we've seen in pop
在流行文化 比如说
cultures in things such as
科幻电影和动作电影中看到的
sci-fi movies and action movies.
我们也自然地接受了
So much so that if I were to go
如果我走进观众席
around the audience and ask
让每个人给我一个
everyone to give me one-word
由深色模式
association of what a dark
联想到的词
interface is to them, I'd get
我肯定会得到这些词
responses such as cool, of
酷 精致 专业
futuristic; and even beautiful.
富有未来感 甚至美丽
So going into the design for
所以深入到深色模式的设计中
Dark Mode, we really wanted to
我们真的
acknowledge all of these
感谢所有的这些
aesthetic associations that we
和深色界面相关的
all have with dark interfaces,
美学形容词
while at the same time embracing
同时享受
a lot of the real benefits that
深色设计给你带来的
a dark design offers you, such
大量切实的好处
as a higher contrast for
比如说排版时的更强对比
typography.
我们意识到深色模式
really, really cool, and that a
真的很酷
lot of you are going to want to
很多人都会把软件调成深色模式
permanently.
一直使用这个模式
But, in actuality, only a small
然而 在实际使用中
subset of apps really should be
只有一小部分 App
dark all the time, and those are
需要处于深色模式
things that are media-centric or
那就是以媒体为中心
content-creation apps.
或内容创造型的 App
Those are the ones that are best
这些 App 最适合
suited to staying dark all the
一直设置成深色模式
time, so if your app doesn't
所以如果你使用的 App
fall into one of those
不属于以上任何一类
categories, it's better to let
那最好让你的 App
your app follow what the system
跟随系统界面样式
appearance is, rather than to
而不是一直调至深色模式
The second principle was that
第二个设计理念是
dark interfaces are not just
黑色界面并不是直接使用反色
And, really, what's at the core
深色模式的核心是
here is that when you look at a
当你看到一个深色界面
dark interface, it can sometimes
有时你会
be easy to think of just taking
想当然地认为
the light interface and
只是把浅色模式
inverting it to end up with your
直接反转了一下颜色
final result.
得到深色模式
But, in actuality, that can be
但是实际上
very creatively limiting, and so
并不完全是这样
it's better to take a look at
黑色界面并不是直接一些要素
application on a case-by-case
并以具体的 App 为例试一下
is the visual cue that they're
看看他们想要带来的
trying to communicate and then
视觉提示
figure out whether an opposite
然后看看相反的视觉提示
visual cue is necessary.
是否是必要的
So, if you take something, for
所以比如说
example, like, a standard Light
如果你采用标准的 Light 普通按钮
push button in the light
在浅色模式下
appearance, the buttons look
这些按钮
like this in their active state.
处于活跃状态
And, then, when you click on
然后当你点按这些按钮时
them, the buttons darken.
它们的颜色就加深了
And this is generally true of
对于几乎所有的操作
almost all of the controls in
都是这样的
the light appearance in that
浅色模式在点按时
version of what their active
会比活跃状态颜色更深
In Dark Mode, however, the
然而 在深色模式中
general active state looks like
大部分的活跃状态是这样的
this, and when you click on
当你点击它们时
them, they brighten, and that,
它们就变亮了
again, is generally true of all
同样 对于几乎所有控件都是一样的
They will all generally brighten
它们几乎都会变亮
up.
另一个例子是组合框
In light appearance, the group
在浅色模式下
boxes have a dark fill behind
组合框是深色填充
them and are shaded such along
边缘有阴影
the edges to give them a
这就给了它们一种
recessed quality such that they
嵌入式的视觉效果
look like they're carved into
看起来像是
the window background that
刻在它们所在的
they're inside of.
窗口背景里
In Dark Mode, however, the group
但是 在深色模式下
boxes are treated almost as if
组合框效果像是自发光
But, at the end of the day, the
但是 总而言之
general purpose of the group box
组合框的作用或者目的
is the same between the two
在这两种模式下
modes in that what they're
是相同的
really trying to communicate to
它们真正想
the user is that the contents
传达给用户的是
contained therein are all
这里面包含的内容
related somehow.
总是相关的
Why I said that it was important
具体分析和尝试
and try and determine what the
看看什么样的视觉提示
visual cue that your elements
是你的要素想要展现的
are trying to communicate-- It's
这是非常重要的
important, is because, in some
它重要是因为
cases, the visual cue that's
在某些情况下
being communicated is already
浅色模式的效果
effective enough in the Light
已经十分有效
Mode and should be left as is in
在深色模式中应该同样有效
An example of this are the
一个例子是
window shadows.
窗口阴影
As we all know, macOS is a
我们都知道
layered window environment, and
macOS 使用的是分层窗口
the window shadows really help
窗口阴影真的可以很好地
to communicate the sense of
展示一种深度感
depth, the Z-depth of the
也就是窗口的 Z 轴深度
So, if we were to have inverted
所以 比如说
the window shadows, for example,
如果我们反转窗口阴影色
and started using a white
比如开始使用白色
UI would have become flat.
整个 UI 会显得扁平化
You would have lost that sense
你会失去那种深度感
Another thing to note is that
还需要强调一点
the window shadows in macOS are
macOS 的窗口阴影
constructed of two layers.
分为两层
We've got the diffused shadow
Diffused Shadow（扩散阴影）
and the rim shadow.
和 Rim Shadow（边缘阴影）
So, if we look at this little
我们放大
portion of the screen and look
屏幕的这一小部分
at how the shadows were
看看阴影是如何
constructed and treated in Dark
在深色模式中进行构建并处理的
Mode, the first thing to note is
第一个要强调的点是
that, in taking into
考虑到用户
consideration that users are
会来回切换
going to be able to go back and
浅色模式
forth between light and dark
和深色模式
appearance quite often and that
而且可能会比较频繁
some apps are going to stay dark
一些 App 也会
all the time, it was important
一直处于深色模式
for us to keep the diffused
所以让扩散阴影保持不变
shadow exactly the same.
非常重要
So, we used the exact same
所以在深色模式下处理窗口阴影时
shadow blur parameters for the
我们使用了完全相同的
shadows in Dark Mode.
阴影模糊参数
Next, we took a look at the rim
然后 我们来看一下
shadows and saw what changes we
边缘阴影
needed to do for those, and the
看一下我们对它们做了什么改变
changes that we did for Dark
我们对深色模式做的改变是
Mode where we adjusted the
调整了不透明度
opacity to make them a little
让不透明度变得
bit higher so that the contrast
稍高一点
edge was more defined and that
边缘的对比
we made them a little bit
更加清晰 更锋利
To further the focus and the
为了加强窗口的
edge detail on the windows, we
重点和边缘细节
added an inner rim stroke to the
我们又给窗口加了一层内层边缘阴影
windows to really help define
这可以使窗口显得轮廓分明
the windows and pop them off.
更加突出
The end result is that the
最终结果是
visual cue still looks very
深色模式的视觉提示
similar to the light appearance,
虽然还和浅色模式很像
but the end result has been
但是最终成品
finely tuned for dark appearance
还是很适合深色模式
so that it works much better.
使得深色模式更出色
The second principle was that
第二个设计理念是
Dark Mode is content focused,
深色模式是内容突出型模式
and this was the one that we
这也是我们在整个设计过程中
actually.
最常提及的一点
When you look at a light
当你看着
interface screen, it can
一个浅色的交互界面
sometimes be a little difficult
有时候很难
to tell what the content is,
去辨别它的内容是什么
where to focus your attention
你需要注意哪些地方
to, especially when there are
尤其是当屏幕上有很多窗口时
And part of the reason for that
部分原因是
is because a lot of the content
我们创造出来的
that we all create is just
很多内容
bright in general.
大部分都是亮色的
However, in a dark UI, the
然而在深色的用户界面
content stands out because of
可以使内容很显眼
the background being pretty
因为它的背景很暗
dark.
所有的窗口外框
background generally just melts
都融于背景
away, and the content becomes
内容就成了
the primary focus of your
你关注的主要焦点
Generally, we found that there
大体上有三种
were three methods for how to
处理窗口
treat your content regions
内容部分的方法
optimize the content focus.
可以使内容更加突出
The first method was to just
第一个方法就是
generally go completely dark.
简单地调成全深色
An app like Finder is a great
“访达”这样的 App
example of where this is
就是个很好的例子
possible because of the way that
因为它内容的展现方式
the content is displayed.
很适合深色模式
Finder's content are displayed
“访达”的内容是以
as colorful file icons and so
多彩的文件图标形式展示的
the dark background really helps
所以深色的背景
the icons stand out as much as
可以让内容尽可能突出
possible.
第二个方式是
the content as is.
不做任何处理
Pages is a great example of what
“Pages 文稿”是一个很好
you see is what you get app,
“所见即所得”的例子
where the contents should be
用户是怎样
rendered and presented exactly
要求和创建内容的
as the user authored and created
内容就应该怎样被渲染和展现出来
Dark Mode is a great UI for what
对于“所见即所得”这类 App 来说
you see is what you get apps,
深色模式是个很好的 UI
because the content really
因为内容
becomes the primary focus, and
会变成主要焦点
the UI really becomes the
而 UI 会变成次要的
secondary focus and almost melts
甚至会在你的
away.
视野中淡出
The third method was to make the
第三个方法
content region appearance a user
把内容部分的外观
option.
留给用户选择
Mail is a good example of an app
“邮件”就是一个很好的例子
where the appearance of the
它内容的样式
content might be ambiguous as to
是不确定的
whether the user would prefer it
取决于用户更喜欢
to be light or dark, and so the
浅色还是深色模式
best thing to do is to make an
所以最好的方式是
application setting so that the
添加一个 App 内设置
user can determine whether they
让用户自己决定
want it to be light or dark on
是使用浅色模式
their own, while their
还是深色模式
application's chrome area still
但你 App 的边框部分
respects the overall system
应该遵循
appearance.
整体系统样式
One thing that all three of
这三种方式的
these windows had in common was
共同点是
that the chrome remained dark
边框一直是深色
and became secondary to the
比起内容部分没那么显眼
And Dark Mode kind of achieves
深色模式通过我们称为
this using a feature that we
“Desktop Tinting（桌面着色）”的功能
call desktop tinting, which
做到了这个效果
causes the window's background
这种功能可以使窗口背景
colors to camouflage themselves
根据桌面图片
with the desktop picture.
自动变色
We found that completely
我们发现
desaturated gray colors have a
一直用不饱和的灰色
tendency to have a color
有可能在某些时候
in conflict with what your
和你桌面图片的色温相冲突
effect was magnified when you
如果你的侧边栏是半透明的
have a translucent sidebar area,
而你的窗口中有
for example, against a solid
完全不透明的区域
opaque area of your window, and
这种效果会更明显
so desktop tinting helps
“Desktop Tinting（桌面着色）”可以
mitigate that.
减弱这种冲突
Once applied, the desktop
使用这个功能
tinting gives the whole window a
可以给你的整个窗口
harmonious color scheme, which
一个和谐的色彩结构
helps it to blend in with the
使其更好地
surrounding areas and really
融入周围区域
reduces that color temperature
减少色温差距
So, how do we do the desktop
那我们要如何
tinting effect?
实现这一效果呢
The first thing that we do is,
首先 我们在
the desktop portion that is
窗口后面的
behind the window, and then we
桌面部分中取样
derive a average color for that
可以得到一个平均色
area, and then we blend that
然后我们把这个颜色
average color with a gray, which
和灰色混合
then becomes the window
这就成为了
background color.
窗口的背景色
This background color is
这个背景色是可变的
dynamic, so as the user moves
当用户在屏幕上
the window around the screen,
移动窗口时
the color will update itself so
颜色会自动改变
that the window always stays in
窗口颜色会一直
sync with the wallpaper portion
和它后面的墙纸部分保持同步
So, if we look at the effect in
所以如果我们看一下
action across a couple of
几个不同壁纸下的
different wallpapers, you can
动态变化效果
see that the window is adjusting
你可以看到右侧的窗口
itself on the right side to
自动调节
match the desktop picture that
以适应后面壁纸的颜色
Not only does the window
不仅是窗口的背景色
background color adjust itself
会自己改变
to take advantage of the desktop
以适应桌面颜色
color, but the controls also get
控件也会
a little bit of that going
稍有变化
through them also due to the
因为控件
control's opacity.
是不透明的
For users that work in
有一些用户
color-sensitive applications or
他们的软件对色彩准确度要求高
have very color-sensitive
或者处理的内容对色彩准确度要求很高
content or just generally would
或者只是不希望
prefer not to have the desktop
在自己的 UI 中
tinting apply to their UI, we
使用这个功能
offer the Graphite Mode so that
我们提供了石墨色模式
they can disable the color
这样就可以全面禁止
tinting altogether.
这个功能
If we take a look at the color
接下来我们看一下
swatches for the window
窗口背景色的色板
background colors, along the top
在最上面
there, we can see the window
我们可以看到在浅色模式下
background color in the Light
windowBackground
Mode, which is the standard
是标准的浅灰色
light gray that we're all
这是我们已经
accustomed to.
习惯了的颜色
And, in the middle there, we've
中间这里
got the under page background
是 underPageBackground
color, which is a mid-tone gray,
以中灰色呈现
and then we've got the content
接下来是 contentBackground
background, which is the white
也就是我们熟悉的
background color that we're all
白色背景
familiar with behind all of our
所有内容后的背景
content areas.
用的都是这个
In the middle row, you can see
在中间这行
how the desktop tinting affects
你可以看到桌面着色
these colors, and, then, along
是如何影响这些颜色的
the bottom, you can see the
同时在下方
effects of the graphite accent
你也可以看到石墨色模式
color disabling the desktop
是如何使桌面着色功能
tinting effect.
失去作用的
So, now that we've gone over
现在我们已经大体介绍了
some of the design principles,
这些设计原则
let's go into a little bit of
接下来给大家介绍一下
the design considerations that
我们的设计考虑
you should take into account
这是你在更新 App 时
when updating your apps.
需要注意的
First, let's talk about colors.
首先是色彩
For macOS 10.14, we added a lot
我们给 macOS 10.14
of colors.
增加了很多配色
We also removed a lot of colors,
我们也去掉了很多颜色
updated some, and, as you can
更新了一些色彩
see behind me, these are some of
从我身后的屏幕上可以看到
our system colors.
这些是我们的系统色
Along the bottom, we've got the
在下方是深色模式下
dark variance of the colors,
对应的系统色变体
and, as you can see, the dark
如你所见
versions are generally a little
深色模式下的系统色变体
bit brighter and more saturated.
整体会更亮 更饱和一点
Rachel and Taylor are going to a
Rachel 和 Taylor 将会
little bit deeper into the color
在稍后进行到
usage during their portion of
他们的部分时
today's session, but, for now, I
更深一步地介绍色彩
just generally want to try and
但是现在我只是想
cover three colors in
试着介绍三种颜色
particular, which are the blues.
这三种颜色都是蓝色系的
Going from left to right, we've
从左到右分别是
got controlAccentColor,
controlAccentColor
systemBlueColor, and linkColor.
systemBlueColor 和 linkColor
Linkcolor, as the name implies,
linkColor 顾名思义
is meant to be applied to links,
是指 App 在链接上的颜色
text links in particular.
尤其是文本类的链接
So, things that are hyperlinks,
所以像是超链接
taking of the user to a website,
把用户链接到一个网页
or a link within your
或者软件内的链接
application that navigates the
可以引导你到
user to another area of your
软件的其他区域
application-- those should be
这些链接的颜色
treated with linkColor.
都是 linkColor
ControlAccentColor and
controlAccentColor
systemBlueColor are really meant
和 systemBlueColor
to be used on controls that have
可以用于
visible borders or button bezel
可见边框或按钮边框背景
backgrounds or for tinted
或者是可着色的 Glyph
ControlAccentColor, as the name
controlAccentColor 顾名思义
implies, is going to respond to
不论系统强调色是什么颜色
whatever the system accent color
它都是和系统色对应的
is set to, in this case, red.
在这个例子中是红色
So, if you have a custom control
所以如果你有一个个性化控件
that is trying to mimic the
想要模仿
appearance of a standard system
标准系统控件的样式
control, or you just have a
或你只是想要一个
control that you would like to
和你所设置的系统色
system appearance is set to, you
匹配的控件
should use controlAccentColor.
你应该使用 controlAccentColor
If you have a control where it's
如果你有一个控件
important that the control stays
它必须是蓝色
blue because of informational
可能是出于信息方面的原因
purposes or for branding
或者是品牌方面的原因
purposes, then systemBlueColor
systemBlueColor
is a better choice for you to
对你来说是
use.
更好的选择
Next, let's take a look at
接下来让我们看一下
designing with vibrancy.
包含 Vibrancy 的设计
When we talk about vibrancy,
谈到 Vibrancy
what we're generally referring
我们一般是指
to is the package of a
一系列的半透明素材
conjunction with the content
和它上面的内容
that is displayed above it.
组成的一个整体
So, in this case, the vibrancy
比如说“访达”的 Vibrancy 效果
is the vibrant Finder sidebar.
在这里就是它的侧边栏
Generally, we have non-colored
总的来说 Vibrancy
artwork that is meant to be
就是动态地
treated vibrantly.
处理未上色的图案
An example of that is the glyphs
比如说这里
and the text in the Finder
“访达”侧边栏的
sidebar here.
Glyph 和文本
The end result of the vibrancy
Vibrancy 效果的结果就是
is is that the colors become
对于文本之类的内容
higher saturation, and the
色彩会变得更饱和
like the text.
对比会更强烈
Colored artwork, such as the
而带有颜色的部分
finder tags in this example,
比如说“访达”中的标记
should be treated as
就应该使用
non-vibrant.
非 Vibrancy 效果
Same thing with colored
带有颜色的图标
iconography.
也是这样的
The vibrancy will destroy the
Vibrancy 效果不会影响
original colors that you have in
图像中原有的色彩
your image, and so you want to
所以带颜色的图标也应使用
treat those as non-vibrant.
非 Vibrancy 效果
So, taking a look at how you can
现在来看一下
construct vibrant content, it
如何实现 Vibrancy 效果
might seem almost obvious to
可能很明显
just use opacities, in this
直接调节不透明度
case, opacities of white.
在这里是白色的不透明度
But while it's true that some
但是一些
color contribution from the
来自背景的色彩
background is occurring through
会对这里的素材有影响
happening because of the
这种情况的出现
opacity-- the end result is
是由于不透明度的最终效果
actually not as highly saturated
实际上不会向我们期望的那样
as we would desire.
那么饱和
And, as you can see along the
你可以看到
bottom with the Quaternary Label
下面的 “Quaternary Label Color”
Color, the legibility is a
会存在一些
little bit compromised.
清晰度上的妥协
Instead, what you want to do is
那么你要做的是
construct these using opaque
用不透明的灰度颜色
grayscale colors.
对它进行处理
One thing to note here is that
这里要强调的一点是
the text color for the RGB label
这些 RGB 标签的文本颜色
colors here are full black.
都是全黑色
What's going to happen once the
应用混合模式后
Blend Mode is applied is that
将会发生的是
the text that is black is going
黑色的文本
to become completely
变成了全透明
So, if you have areas of your
所以如果你有一些内容
content that need to be treated
需要突出出来
as a knockout, use full opaque
那就使用不透明黑色
black, and if you have areas
如果一些区域
that need to be gradiate towards
你想要它渐变到不透明
an opacity, use a gray that is
那就使用
ramping itself towards a full
趋向不透明黑色的灰色
This is true in Dark Mode, and
深色模式是这样
the opposite is true in Light
浅色模式也是这样
Mode, in light, vibrant areas, I
在浅色变色区
should say, where white full,
这里不透明的纯白色
opaque white is full transparent
代表着完全透明
and gradiating towards that is
向其渐变
going to give you a
就会达到透明的效果
So, once we apply the vibrancy,
所以当我们使用 Vibrancy 效果时
we can see that the gray colors
我们可以看到灰色
become a lot more saturated, and
变得饱和了许多
the legibility of the Quaternary
“Quaternary Label Color”
Color Label is a lot more
的清晰度也得到了显著提升
Putting them side by side, we
两相对比
can see just how much of a
我们可以看到
difference there is between the
不透明构造
opacity construction, versus the
和灰度构造
grayscale construction.
有多大的差异
In some cases, over certain
在一些情况下 对于特定的一些色彩
colors, the opacity construction
不透明效果会很成功
will fly, but it's not exactly
但是 在美学或者在清晰度角度
aesthetically or legibility
这并不是
wise.
最好的结果
Next, let's take a look at
现在我们看一下
artistically inverting glyphs,
艺术性反转 Glyph
and, by artistically inverting,
艺术性反转
what I'm referring to is the
指的是一个过程
process of creatively looking at
你需要创造性地
your glyphs and determining what
观察你的 Glyph
areas need to be adjusted to
并确定什么区域
take advantage of the Dark Mode,
需要做出调整 以适应深色模式
So, here we've got a set of our
这里有一些
standard glyphs that we have in
需要做出调整标准 Glyph
One thing to note is that the
需要注意的是
light appearances glyphs
浅色模式的 Glyph
generally use a lot of edge
大多使用了很多边框
strokes with hollow centers.
中间是空白的
And the reason for that is that
这样做的原因是
we take advantage of the white
我们利用白色背景
backgrounds that these are
把这些简单地放在上面
generally placed on top of in
来更好地
order to denote form and shape.
展现它们的形状
But, if we were to take these
但是如果我们把
exact same vector forms and
完全一样的矢量图形
place them over a dark
放在深色背景上
background, all of that sense of
所有的形状感和体积感
form and volume is kind of lost,
都仿佛消失了
and so we had to artistically
所以我们要
invert them to bring back some
艺术地反转它们
of that sense of form and
强化它们的形状和体积
Looking at how some of these are
看看其中的一些
constructed, we've got a couple
是如何构建的
of simple examples, like this
我们有几个简单的例子
finder tag.
比如这个“访达”标记
On the left side, it's denoting
在左侧有一个白色的标记
a white tag with a dark eyelet
上面有一个黑色的小孔
On the right side, however, in
然而在右侧
Dark Mode, that sense of it
深色模式下
being a white sheet of paper is
纸片的感觉消失了
So, once we invert it, we get
一旦我们把颜色翻转一下
back that white sheet of paper
就能找回纸片的感觉
with an eyelet knockout hole.
上面还有一个小孔
Looking at how this is
来看看这是如何构建的
constructed, generally, what you
大体上你要做的是
would do is expand the clipping
扩大剪裁路径
paths, I should say, and then
然后选中小孔形状
then reverse the knockout on
然后将它的颜色反转
that.
所以这只是个
selecting any redundant vector
选择多余的矢量路径
paths and removing those.
然后删除的简单操作
Taking a look at a slightly more
看一个稍微复杂一点的形状
complex shape, for example, the
比如说这个房子
We've got a white house on the
左侧有一个白色的房子
left side, and on the right
但在右侧
side, the house isn't white
房子不再是白色了
So, inverting it returns us back
颜色反转让我们重新得到
to a white painted house.
一个白色的房子
Generally, the construction for
大体上这个 Glyph 的构建
this is about the same as the
和刚刚的过程是一样的
other process, but one important
但是对于这个 Glyph
aspect of this glyph, in
尤其重要的一点是
particular, was that we have to
我们需要
add a new shape into the vector
在矢量图形上加上一个新的形状
In this case, we're mimicking
这种情况下
the roof line, creating a shadow
我们要模仿屋顶的线
underneath the roof that we're
在屋顶下再创造一个阴影
going to knock out.
然后把它删除
And this is important, because
这一步很重要
if we were to have left the
如果构建房子时
construction of the house
不加这个阴影线
roof would have no definition,
这个屋顶就不会突出出来
and it would be really hard to
当它在一些小的视图中
see that at small size.
就更难看清楚
Moving on to a more complicated
接下来是一个更复杂的 Glyph
glyph, like this mail envelope,
我们用这个邮件信封
for example.
作为例子
On the left side, we can see a
左侧 我们可以看到体积感和形状感
We've got two layers, generally.
大体上说 这个 Glyph 可以分为两层
We've got the back flap of the
一层是信封后面的封皮
envelope, and we've got the
另一层是
front flap of the envelope with
信封前面的封皮
a letter contained in between.
中间有一封信
On the right side, a lot of that
在右侧 质量感消失了
because of the lack of fill
因为缺少填充色
And so, once we invert that, we
所以当反转这个图像时
return back to having a sense of
我们要重新赋予它质量感
Again, generally, the process of
同样地 大体上
construction for this one is
这个 Glyph 的构建
about the same as some of the
和之前的是一样的
other ones, but it's a little
但是多出了一些细节
bit more detailed and time
需要更多的时间
consuming just due to the number
因为这里有
of paths that there are.
更多的剪辑路径
But, generally, what you want to
但是大体上
do is break it apart into two
你要把这个分成两部分
pieces, again, so that you have
你再一次得到了
the front and the rear portion,
前面的封面和后面的封皮
and then you have your letter
中间是信件部分
One important detail that this
一个重要的细节是
glyph exemplifies is the dual
这个 Glyph 例证了
opacities that we use in some of
我们在一些 Glyph 中使用的
our glyphs.
双重不透明度
In this case, the letter is set
在这种情况下
to 80% opacity in order to make
信件的不透明度设置成 80%
it secondary to the envelope,
使它和信封相比 处于次要的位置
itself, being opened, which is
信封 处于打开的状态
what we're trying to
是我们想要传递的信息
And the opposite is true in
相反的情况对于浅色模式
Light Mode also, where we do use
同样适用
80% opacities, in some cases,
我们在一些情况下
also.
也会使用 80% 的不透明度
So, quickly wrapping up what
现在让我们迅速回顾一下
we've covered so far.
刚才讲过的内容
Dark interfaces are cool, so
深色界面很酷
cool that you're probably going
酷到让你
to want to make your app
想把 App
potentially dark all the time,
一直设置在深色模式上
but unless your app is a
但是如果你的 App
creative or media-centric app,
不是设计类或媒体类 App
you should reconsider that, and,
那你就要重新考虑一下
instead make your app follow
让你的软件
what the system appearance is
和系统外观
set to, instead.
保持一致
Don't limit your app design to
不要把深色模式的设计
just inverting your existing
简单地理解为
light appearance, and, instead,
浅色模式的反转
take a look at what elements are
要具体分析你的
in your app on a case-by-case
App 中的各个元素
basis, and try and determine
尝试并看一下
what are the visual cues that
什么样的视觉提示
are trying to be communicated by
是深色模式想要通过控件传递的
the controls, and then determine
然后确定
whether an opposite visual cue
相反的视觉提示
is necessary or not.
是否是必要的
Then take a look at what type of
然后看一下
content your app produces or
你的软件提供或展示什么内容
displays, and then use that as a
然后用这些
guidance to determine what type
指导你去确定
of method to use for how to
你想将内容部分
treat your content area--
设置成哪种模式
whether to go fully dark,
是保持当前的全深色
or whether to make it a user
还是通过软件内设置
option via the app settings.
让用户自己选择
Then, taking a look at colors,
然后我们大致看了色彩
generally, you want to make sure
确保你恰当地使用
colors that we went over,
我们刚才介绍的三种颜色
appropriately, if you have
如果你的控件是
controls that are text controls,
文本控件
try using text link if it's
而且可能会用到文本链接
applicable.
就用 linkColor
If you have controls that you
如果你想要控件
want to follow the system accent
遵循系统的强调色
color appearance, set those to
那就把控件颜色设置成
control accent color, and if you
controlAccentColor
have a control that has to stay
如果你想让控件
blue all the time, adopt system
一直保持蓝色
blue color.
那就使用 systemBlueColor
And then Taylor and Rachel are
接下来 Taylor and Rachel
going to go into a lot more
会非常详细地介绍
detail about color uses, so
色彩使用问题
definitely pay attention to
所以一定要
their section.
关注他们的部分
When constructing your vibrancy
当构建你的 Vibrancy 区域时
areas, make sure that you're
需要确保
constructing them in a way that
你构建它们的方式
takes full advantage of the
能充分利用
vibrant effect blending, so make
动态效果混合
sure that you're using grayscale
也就是要确保你使用的是
colors that are opaque.
不透明的灰度颜色
And if you have areas that need
如果你想突出某些区域
to be knockouts or have
或者让它们不透明
opacities, ramp towards black in
在深色模式下趋向于黑色
Dark Mode or ramp towards white
或者在浅色模式下
in Light Mode.
趋向于白色
And then, lastly, make sure that
最后 确保你使用的 Glyph
artistically inverted in order
是经过艺术反转的
to showcase the intent that the
尽可能有效地
glyphs are trying to communicate
向用户展示
to the user as effectively as
Glyph 的
possible.
设计意图
Finally, make sure to go to the
最后确保 前往 “Human
Human Interface Guidelines to
Interface Guidelines（人机界面准则）”
see more design guidance.
查看更多的设计引导
And then as well as checking the
然后注意检查
design resources section, where,
设计资源部分
by the end of the month, we're
这个月底我们会
updated Photoshop, and sketch
更新 Photoshop 和 Sketch 模板
templates, and kits for you to
以及工具包 供你使用
And with that, I'd like to hand
接下来我想
it off to Rachel to go over some
把时间交给 Rachel
details on how to adopt and
有请她介绍一些
support Dark Mode.
采用和支持深色模式的细节
Thanks
谢谢
[ Applause ]
[ 掌声 ]
&gt;&gt; Thank you, Raymond.
&gt;&gt; 谢谢你 Raymond
Hello everybody.
大家好
Let's take a moment just to
让我们用一点点时间
thank Raymond and the rest of
来感谢 Raymond
the design team for designing
和其他设计团队的成员
Dark Mode.
设计出深色模式
Isn't it awesome?
深色模式是不是很棒
[ Applause ]
[ 掌声 ]
Now Taylor and I will take you
现在我和 Taylor 会向大家介绍
through the engineering basics
在 macOS Mojave 上
of adopting Dark Mode in macOS
采用深色模式的
Mojave.
工程基础知识
A while back, Taylor and I were
在之前我和 Taylor 聊天时
chatting, and we discovered that
发现我俩都
we were both huge fans of
非常喜欢变色龙
And while we don't yet own our
尽管我们现在还没有
own pet chameleons, we thought
养自己的变色龙宠物
we'd be prepared by writing an
但是我们会通过编写一个名为
app called Chameleon Wrangler.
《Chameleon Wrangler》的 App 来做好准备
We did this back in High Sierra,
我们在 High Sierra 上编写了这个 App
and so we thought, "Hey, let's
所以我们觉得应该更新它
update it for Mojave."
以适应 Mojave
The first thing we did was put
我们做的第一件事
our system in Dark Mode and
就是把我们的系统设成深色模式
launch our app from the dock.
并在程序坞启动了我们的 App
And it didn't really look too
看起来并不是很暗
In fact, it's exactly the same
实际上它在浅色和深色模式下
between light and dark.
是一样的
And you'll note throughout this
而且你会注意到
portion of the talk that on the
在我们的介绍部分
left, when we want to compare,
当我们想要对比的时候
we'll have the light on the left
会把浅色模式放在左边
and the dark on the right, so
深色模式放在右边
you can compare them side by
你就可以
side.
一一对比了
Can't actually run the system
真正运行的时候
this way.
不是这样的
It's just for show.
这样只是为了展示
So, what we needed to do was
现在我们要
link against the 10.14 SDK and
把 10.14 SDK 关联到
Xcode 10.
Xcode 10 上
We built and ran our app, and
我们构建并运行 App
voila.
你看 变暗了许多
Comparing with light, you can
和浅色模式相比
see a lot of things are
你可以看到
different and darker,
很多东西都不同了 自动变暗了
automatically, but there's still
但是依旧有一些东西
some things we'd like to fix up.
我们想要调整一下
So, we'll go into detail about
所以我们会深入探讨一下一些色彩
There's a lot of colors.
我们用了很多色彩
Let's take a look at this header
看一下标题区
area that's light green.
是浅绿色
We implemented this using a
我们是通过硬编码颜色
hardcoded color, where we
来实现这个颜色的
specified our custom RGBA
并且指定了我们的
values.
自定义 RGBA 值
The problem with this approach
这一方案的问题是
is that it doesn't change
在不同的外观下
between the different
它不会发生改变
You're stuck with the same color
它会保持这一个颜色
no matter what the system
无论你的
preference setting is.
系统偏好设置是什么
Instead of doing it this way,
我们并未采用这一方案
we're going to take advantage of
相反我们准备利用
colors in asset catalogs.
“Asset Catalog（素材目录）”中的色彩
You've been able to do this
早在 10.13 版本你就可以
since 10.13-- have colors in
在素材目录取色了
asset catalogs, but now you can
但是现在你可以
specify colors for different
为不同的外观
appearances.
选择不同的颜色
So, we've added a dark version
所以我们已经添加了
of our header color.
标头色彩的深色版本
Asset catalog colors have
素材目录
several advantages.
有几个优点
You can give them meaningful
你可以给它们起有意义的名字
names that describe where the
来描述它们被用在哪里
color is used or how it is used,
或者是如何被使用的
and those are often called
这些名字被称为
semantic names.
语义化名称
You can have multiple
你可以有多套
definitions of the color, as I
色彩设定
showed you, with the light and
就像我通过浅色模式和深色模式
dark versions and also for
进行展示的
different color spaces-- sRGB
或者针对不同的色彩空间的设定
versus P3.
比如 sRGB 和 P3 色域
And it gives you a central
它给了你一个
location for defining all of
能定义所有颜色的集中区域
That makes it easy to go in and
而且可以使你在需要的时候
tweak your colors without
轻松地进入并且调节颜色
changing any code if needed.
无需改变任何代码
So, here's our color now in a
这就是我们
asset catalog, and it's called
素材目录的颜色
headerColor, because it's the
它们被称为 headerColor
header color.
因为它们是标头的颜色
And let's see how it looks now,
让我们看一下使用 headerColor
using headerColor.
目前是什么样子的
Looks a lot better and dark with
使用了深绿色之后
that dark green.
看起来好多了 颜色深多了
But something becomes obvious,
但是也暴露了一些问题
and that's the text.
那就是文本
Chloe's name and age are hard to
Chloe 的名字和年龄
read now against the darker
在绿色加深的情况下
green.
变得难以辨识
Things looked okay in light, but
在浅色模式下看起来很好的
they don't look good in dark.
在深色模式下变得不好了
Well, there, we were using black
这里我们当时使用了黑色
and dark gray, and those are
和深灰色
static colors, also.
这些也是静态颜色
Not exactly the same as
和硬编码不完全一样
hardcoded, because we're using
因为我们使用的是
available colors, but they don't
素材目录中的颜色
change.
但是它们不会变色
So, instead of using asset
所以与之使用
catalogs this time, we're going
素材目录的颜色
to take advantage of dynamic
我们这次准备利用
system colors.
动态系统色
NSColor has many dynamic colors
NSColor 有许多的动态色彩
available for you to use with
可供我们使用
definitions across the different
不同的外观下都有
appearances.
不同的设定
And a special thing about
NSColor 的一个特点是
NSColor is that the colors are
色彩在绘制之前
resolved at draw time, which
是经过处理的
means that the actual RGBA
也就是说
values that are used depend on
真正使用的 RGBA 值
the circumstances at the time
取决于色彩被画出来时的情况
I'm going to go through some
现在我带大家浏览几个
examples of dynamic system
关于动态系统色的例子
Starting with the label colors
从 Raymond 先前谈过的
that Raymond talked about
labelColor 开始
earlier, and I'm showing the
现在我向大家展示的
dynamic colors on the top half
上半部分是动态色
and some corresponding static
在下半部分是一些
colors just using black in
对应的静态色
varying levels of opacity on the
只是一些不透明度不同的黑色
And, as you can see, in the
大家可以看到
light appearance, everything
在浅色模式
looks fine.
一切看起来都不错
But over in dark, labelColor
但是在深色模式
looks great still, but the black
labelColor 看起来依旧很好
colors disappear against the
但是黑色消失在了
dark background.
深色背景之中
Here's an example in the system
下面例子是“邮箱”
in Mail of where labelColor and
它同时使用了
secondaryLabelColor are used.
labelColor 和 secondaryLabelColor
The more important text is given
最重要的文本
the labelColor, and the less
用了 labelColor
important text is
次要的文本
secondaryLabelColor.
用的是 secondaryLabelColor
To find out which colors are
为了弄清楚哪种颜色是动态色
dynamic, in the Interface
在 “Interface Builder（界面构建器）”的
Builder popup menu for colors,
色彩弹出菜单中
it'll show you the list, and
它会给你一个列表
they've done a really nice job
我的同事真的很棒
of making those be the dynamic
他们把很多颜色都变成了动态颜色
So, now switching, once we know
现在我们知道怎么做了
that, black color and dark gray
把黑色和深灰色
to labelColor and
转换成 labelColor 和 secondaryLabelColor
secondaryLabelColor, this fixes
这就解决了文本问题
our text, and it looks great in
在浅色模式和深色模式下
both light and dark.
看起来都不错
A little bit more about dynamic
关于动态系统色我还要补充一点
As Raymond showed you, there are
正如 Raymond 向大家展示的
a bunch of colorful system
我们有很多系统色
colors-- systemRed,
systemRed
systemYellow, systemGreen are
systemYellow 和 systemGreen
just three examples.
只是其中的三个例子
And they subtly change for the
并且它们会发生微妙的变化
different appearances so that
展现出不同的外观
they look great in both places,
使自己在两种模式下都能很好看
as opposed to the static, plain
和静态的 平淡的
red, yellow, green colors.
红 黄 绿色不同
Another special thing about
动态色还有一点比较特殊
using systemRed, etc., is that
在使用 systemRed 等色彩时
they will match other uses of
它们会应用到整个系统中
systemRed throughout the OS as
其它用到它的地方
well as matching on iOS.
甚至还会在 iOS 上应用
So, it's great to stick to these
所以当你的颜色中
kinds of colors when you have an
有信息类文本时
informational content in your
一直使用这类颜色是很好的选择
color.
比如说 需要使用红色或黄色的警告
Raymond also talked about
Raymond 还提及了
linkColor, systemBlue, and
linkColor systemBlue
controlAccentColor, so I wanted
和 controlAccentColor
to talk about that again.
我想再介绍一下这几种色彩
LinkColor and systemBlue are
linkColor 和 systemBlue
very similar but slightly
非常相像
different and use linkColor for
但是稍有不同
actual links to webpages or for
对你 App 中的网页链接
going someplace in your app,
或导航到 App 中的其他位置需要使用 linkColor
whereas systemBlue is used for
而在软件的标准操作中
standard actions in your
应该使用 systemBlue
application, or you might even
你甚至可能用
use controlAccentColor if you
controlAccentColor
want to match the system
去匹配系统偏好设置
preference, in this case,
在这里 我们使用的是紫色
You may search through your
你可能搜索
application code and find all
你的软件代码
the places you're using color
找到使用颜色的部分
and fix it all up and then still
把它们全改过来
end up with a situation like
但是结果可能依旧是这个情况
this, where, for some reason,
出于某些原因
even though your text switched
即便是你的文本改变了颜色
color, there's something behind
它后面的颜色
it that's still drawing wrong.
依旧是不对的
And if you're stuck and can't
如果你陷入了这种困境
figure out what to do, I suggest
不知所措
taking advantage of Xcode's View
我建议你利用 Xcode 的 “View Debugger
Debugger.
（视图调试器）”
I'm just going to cover this
在这里 我只是简单介绍一下
Dark Mode session will go into
在高级深色模式讨论会中
more detail about debugging tips
会详细介绍
and tricks.
有关调试的建议和技巧
So, I can see that light view is
我们可以看到浅色视图
actually my scroll view, and I
实际上是一个滚动视图
had set in the interface builder
之前在 Interface Builder 中
to a custom gray color.
设置为自定义灰色
That's why I couldn't find it
这就是为什么我搜索代码
searching through my code.
却找不到它
So, I switched it to the default
所以我把它转换成
background color, and now
默认背景色
everything looks great.
现在一切看起来都很棒了
And while we're here on this
既然我们展示的是
text view, I'd like to go
文本视图的效果
through some of the colors in
我想在这里向大家
play here that are dynamic
分析一遍这里用到的
system colors that also may be
动态系统颜色 可能也会
useful to you.
对你有所帮助
First, there's textColor, which
首先是 textColor
is switching between black and
在黑色和白色之间转换
white; textBackgroundColors
textBackgroundColor
switches from white to black;
从白色转换成黑色
selectedTextColor goes from
selectedTextColor
black to white; and then
从黑色转换成白色
selectedTextBackgroundColor,
然后 selectedTextBackgroundColor 是蓝色
But you can see it's two
但是你可以看出来
different versions of blue, and
这是两种不同的蓝色
this is special, because it
这一点很特殊
follows the system preference
因为它跟随了
for the highlight color.
高亮色的系统偏好
And you can see, when the
大家可以看到
highlight color changes, the
当高亮显示颜色改变时
selectedTextBackgroundColor
selectedTextBackgroundColor
changes with it.
会随之改变
Now, I'd like to move along and
现在我继续往下讲
talk about accessibility.
谈一谈辅助功能
In the Accessibility display
在辅助功能的
preferences, there's the
显示器偏好设置中
Increase contrast checkbox.
有一个“提高对比度”复选框
If we turn on Increase contrast
如果我们开启提高对比度模式
mode, you'll see that colors and
你可以看到整个系统的
artwork throughout the system
颜色和插图都变了
change to make the UI easier to
这使得视力不好的人
vision.
更容易看清 UI
Well, now in asset catalogs, we
现在在素材目录
can add colors specially for the
我们可以为高对比度外观
high contrast appearances as
专门添加几种颜色
So, here I've added to my header
这里我给标头色
color a version for high
添加了高对比浅色和高对比深色
And this is how Chameleon
这就是《Chameleon Wrangler》
Wrangler now looks in the dark
在对比度深色模式下的外观
You'll notice that not only is
你会发现
my header color using that
不仅我的标题色
special color that I defined,
是我设定的特殊颜色
the rest of the system colors
其他的系统色彩
are also specially defined for
也被特殊设定成
the high contrast appearances.
高对比度外观
And this is true for light high
对于浅色模式下的高对比度
contrast, as well.
也是一样的
Now I'd like to move along and
接下来要讲的是图像
We'll take a look at the toolbar
看一下这里的
buttons here.
工具栏按钮
This chameleon color picker
这个变色龙取色器按钮
button looks pretty good in
在浅色模式下看起来很棒
light, but in dark, that dark
但是在深色模式下
outline disappears against the
深色的轮廓
dark background of the button.
在按钮的深色背景中消失了
So, we'd like to have a special
所以我们应该为深色外观
version of it for the dark
设计一个新的版本
appearance, and, once again, we
我们再一次
turn to our asset catalog friend
求助于我们的朋友 也就是素材目录
and add a version for the dark
添加一个
appearance.
深色外观下的版本
And now it looks much better
现在看起来就好多了
against the dark button with the
深色的按钮和白色的轮廓
light outline.
对比鲜明
That's great for full color
这种方法对全彩图像来说非常棒
How about these other two
那对于这两个按钮来说呢
Well, they already look pretty
它们看起来
good.
已经很棒了
We didn't have to do anything,
我们不需要再做任何修改
so why?
但是为什么呢
Why are these right?
为什么这两个没问题呢
Well, that's because we had made
这是因为 我们已经让这些图像
these images template images.
成为了 “Template Image（模板图像）”
To tell you a little bit about
向大家简单介绍一下
template images, in case you
模板图像
don't already know about them,
大家可能之前不了解
it's important to understand
要明白的是
that the transparency of each
每个像素的透明度
pixel is maintained, but the
保持了原状
color is ignored.
但系统会忽视颜色
You can make the starting image
你可以把初始图像
any color you like, that's
设置成任何颜色 没影响
It's only the transparency.
只和透明度有关
They can be bitmaps or PDFs.
图像可以是 BMP 格式或者 PDF 格式
And here's an example from the
这里有一个例子
OS of the speaker volume image.
macOS 的音量图像
The original image is black, and
原本的图像是黑色
then it has this partially
在更大声波的区域
transparent section for the
有一个部分透明区域
And if we put this image into an
如果我们把这个图像
NSImageView, it's automatically
放入 NSImageView
given the Secondary Label Color,
它会自动变成 secondaryLabelColor
and you can see in light, it's a
可以看到在浅色模式中
medium gray, and in dark, it's a
是中灰色
lighter gray.
在深色模式中灰色变浅了
And then the partially
并且部分透明区域
contrast against the background.
和背景的对比变弱了
Another advantage of using
使用模板图像的
template images is that they
另一个好处是
automatically pick up on the
系统会自动获取按钮状态
When a button is disabled, the
当按钮被禁用时
images are dimmer, and that's
图像会变暗
handled for you if you use
如果你使用模板图像
template images.
就可以自动解决
Okay. So, Chameleon Wrangler is
好 现在《Chameleon Wrangler》
now looking pretty good.
看起来很棒
We got our colors sorted out.
我们让颜色突出了
We got some of our images sorted
一些图像也突出了
out, but there's more to the
但是对于这个 App
application than what you see
还有一些东西要讲
here, so I'd like to invite
所以我想邀请 Taylor
Taylor to the stage to tell you
到台上来
about the rest of it.
给大家介绍一下剩余部分
Thank you very much.
非常感谢大家
[ Applause ]
[ 掌声 ]
&gt;&gt; Thank you Rachel.
&gt;&gt; 谢谢你 Rachel
Now that Rachel's covered a lot
刚才 Rachel 已经介绍了
of the fundamentals of having
很多基本信息
our colors and images react
关于我们如何使色彩和图像
appropriately for Dark Mode,
在深色模式中有合适的响应
let's first take a look at
那么现在我们先来看一下
applying some of those to some
在 App 中
more detailed areas of our
它们具体是如何被应用的
First up is Moodometer, where we
首先是 “Moodometer（情绪指示器）”
can keep track of Chloe's mood
我们可以追踪一天中
shifts throughout the day.
Chloe 的情绪变化
You can see here that the
你可以看到这里
popover's background has
弹出框的背景
automatically adjusted for the
已经自动为深色模式做出调整
However, the button content is
但是背景上的
way too dark, still, on top of
按钮内容
the background.
还是太暗了
Taking a look at our Asa
看一下我们的素材目录
Catalog, we can see that we've
可以看到
prebuilt these images with the
我们已经在素材目录中
color defined in the asset
用颜色预先构建了
themself.
这些图像
So, we can use the technique
所以我们可以使用
that Rachel showed us, where we
Rachel 展示的方法
add a dark variant for those
为这些图像
images with a lighter color.
加一个颜色更浅的深色版本
However, it's kind of
但是 只改变这些图像的填充色
varying the fill color of these
而保持它们原有的形状
images but keeping the same
看起来有些不好
So, there's probably a better
可能还有更好地解决方案
way, and, in Mojave, there is,
在 Mojave 中
using this contentTintColor API.
有一个 contentTintColor API
With this, you can create a
通过使用它
template image and provide a
你可以得到一个模板图像
custom tint color to be used
并且可以使用 customTintColor
instead of the default
而不是默认的
appearance sensitive one.
根据外观变化的图像
That will be used as the base
它可以在任何出现图像的地方
fill color for any of the places
被用作基础填充色
So, we can set the content tint
所以我们可以在 NSImageView 上
color on an NSImageView to tint
设置一个 contentTintColor
its image or on an NSButton to
去给图像着色
tint both its boot image and
或在 NSButton 上设置一个
title.
去给图像和标题着色
So, let's take a look at
现在我们来看一下
adopting this.
它的应用过程
The first step here is to
第一步是
convert these to simple template
把它们转化成普通模板图像
images and remember to set the
记住要把渲染模式
render mode to be the template
设置成模板效果
Taking a look at Chameleon
现在再看一下《Chameleon Wrangler》
Wrangler now, we can see that
我们可以看到
these images are now getting the
这些图像有了一种
default templating effect, which
默认模板效果
looks great in Dark Mode, but
在深色模式下很好看
the next step is going to be
下一步就是
applying that color.
应用这个颜色
So, we could just pull the color
我们可以直接把这个颜色
out of the asset, add a dark
从素材中拖出来
variant, and set the
添加一个深色版本
contentTintColor on these
然后把这些按钮的 contentTintColor
buttons to be that named color.
设置成刚才那个颜色
And this button will
这个按钮
automatically pick the right
会根据系统是浅色模式
variant based on whether it's
还是深色模式
appearing in the light
自动选择
appearance or dark appearance.
正确的变色
However, Rachel also showed us
Rachel 还向我们展示了
how there are a number of
很多系统色是如何
already have these light and
早就已经有了
dark variants, which we could
自己的浅色和深色版本的
use instead.
我们可以直接使用
For instance, we could use
比如我们可以直接使用
systemRed, systemYellow, and
systemRed systemYellow
systemGreen, which, if we return
和 systemGreen
back to Chameleon Wrangler, we
回到《Chameleon Wrangler》
can see looks really great and
我们可以看到真的很棒
has those buttons pop on top of
背景上方的按钮都很突出
What's really cool about this
这项功能很酷的地方
combination is that not only do
不仅在于
we get a very specific green
我们可以得到一个很特殊的绿色
color for both Light and Dark
对于浅色模式和深色模式都可使用
Mode, but with the content tint
而且还在于借助 contentTintColor API
API, the system effects applied
应用于其上的系统效果
on top of that vary based on
也根据模式外观发生改变
As Raymond discussed, in the
正如 Raymond 所说
light appearance, there's a
在浅色模式下
darkening effect on top of that
在基础着色之上
base tint color.
有一个加深的效果
Meanwhile, in the dark
同时 在深色模式下
brightening effect.
有一个提亮的效果
All of these effects are further
所有的这些效果
customized for the increased
可以进一步个性化
contrast setting without any
以加强对比
changes from our application.
同时不需要在 App 中做出任何改变
So, it's really great that we
所以这个功能真的很棒
didn't have to specify all 12 of
我们不需要一一专门设置
these colors.
这 12 种颜色
And instead, we specified a
我们只需要专门设定
single one and, thanks to
一个颜色
dynamic system colors and
然后因为动态系统色
dynamic system effects, we got
和动态系统效果
all of this completely
我们就自动得到了所有的颜色
So, our Moodometer is looking
现在我们的情绪指示器
great.
看起来很棒
Next, we can step over to
接下来是
another type of app where we
我们 App 中的另一个标签页
keep track of very important
我们可以用它追踪
information about Chloe, such as
关于 Chloe 的重要信息
how stressed she's feeling or
比如她压力多大
more importantly, what's her
或者更重要的
favorite type of berry?
她最喜欢哪一种莓
We can see here that this
这里我们可以看到
already looks great, because we
已经很棒了
are using stock Cocoa controls,
因为我们现在用的是常规的 Cocoa 控件
which automatically adjust for
它可以自动调节
Dark Mode.
以适应深色模式
We can see how it reacts to the
我们可以看到
accent color feature that
它对强调色做出何种反应
Raymond talked about by opening
Raymond 刚才介绍过
up system preferences, changing
打开系统偏好
the color to a nice chameleon
把颜色设置成好看的变色龙条纹黄色
striped yellow, and returning
然后回到
back to Chameleon Wrangler.
《Chameleon Wrangler》
We can, again, see that the
我们可以再次看到
built-in controls automatically
内置控件
adjust to that yellow accent
自动调整为黄色强调色
color, including the focus ring
包括聚焦环的颜色
and highlight color.
和高亮显示色
However, we can notice that our
然而我们可以注意到
custom tab bar has remained
自定义标签栏依旧是蓝色
blue, even though we've changed
即便我们已经改变了强调色
Because this blue doesn't really
因为这个蓝色对于我们的
have any significance for our
App 来说并不重要
application, we probably want it
所以我们可能希望
to be following that accent
它能跟随黄色强调色
color.
正如 Rachel 刚才所说
have a few different colors that
我们有几种不同的颜色
will follow the users' accent
会跟随用户的
and highlight color selection.
强调色和高亮显示色选择
New in Mojave is a control
Mojave 中的新特点是
accent color, which you can use
你可以直接用 controlAccentColor
to directly mimic the accented
模仿系统控件的强调色
areas on system controls, such
比如说 弹出式按钮的边缘
default push buttons, or the
默认的点按按钮
selected segment of a segmented
或者一个分段控件的选定分段
There's also selected content
还有一个 selectedContentBackgroundColor
background color, which is what
是指比如说
you see in the background of
你在选定表格行
selected table rows, and you can
看到的背景
use to indicate custom
你可以用它引导
selection.
自定义选取
And selected text background
而 selectedTextBackgroundColor
color is exactly what it sounds
指的是选定文本的背景颜色
So, going back to our app, we
回到我们的软件上
can see that we're using system
可以看到我们正在使用 systemBlueColor
blue color for this custom tab
作为这个自定义选项卡的选择
selection, and, instead, we can
我们也可以
just swap that over to using
直接换过来
controlAccentColor.
使用 controlAccentColor
The next problem here with the
关于自定义选项卡的下一个问题
tab bar is a little more subtle.
有一点更微妙
If we bring our cursor over and
如果我们把光标移过来
press down on it, we can see
点击一下 可以看到
that we're getting a darkening
我们得到了一个变暗的效果
effect instead of the
而不是深色模式应该有的
should in Dark Mode.
提亮的效果
This is because we are taking
这是因为我们
that base color and just
取了那个基础色
applying a constant 30%
而且只对它应用了
darkening effect to it, assuming
恒定的 30% 变暗效果
that would look fine in the
使它会在浅色模式下
light appearance.
比较好看
Instead, we want to describe
与其这样做 我们更应该
something that basically this
描述这个颜色
color is being pressed, and that
被点按后的变化
semantic description can carry
那么这个语义化描述
whatever effect it needs to in
不论是在浅色
the light versus dark
还是深色模式下
appearance.
就都会很准确
So, with the new system effect
所以通过这种 Mojave 的 NSColor 的
API in Mojave on NSColor, we can
全新系统效果 API
describe that exact semantic.
我们可以描述确切的语义
We can take our base color of
我们可以把基础色
controlAccentColor, say that we
当作 controlAccentColor
want to get the pressed variant,
如果我们想要得到点击后的变体
and it will react appropriately
它无论是在浅色模式
in both the light and dark
还是深色模式
appearance.
都会呈现合适的颜色
There's one more area of our
我们 App 中还有
application where you can see
一个能看到
the accent color, and that's in
强调色的区域
this photo browser where we draw
就是图片浏览器
a selection ring around the
我们在图片被选择时
selected photo.
会画一个选择框
Here, we were using the
我们这里用的是
selectedContentBackgroundColor,
selectedContentBackgroundColor
and that, again, automatically
它现在能根据用户
adjusts based on the user's
选择的强调色
selected accent.
自动调整了
Let's open up one of these
让我们打开
photos and take a look at a
这些照片中的一张
nice, big, beautiful photo of
看看 Chloe 这张
Chloe.
又大又漂亮的照片
The first thing that stands out
我们第一眼就注意到了
is the fact that the background
背景没有调成
has not adjusted for Dark Mode.
深色模式
It's still using its light
它依旧是浅色模式中的
translucency effect similar to a
半透明效果
hardcoded color.
像硬编码颜色一样
This effect is provided by
这种效果是
NSVisualEfffectView, which
NSVisualEffectView 提供的
provides the translucent blur
它提供了你看到的
materials you see across the
整个系统的
system.
半透明模糊素材
For instance, there's the
比如说这是一个侧边栏
sidebars which blur onto the
模糊了桌面
desktop and other windows behind
还有它后面的其他窗口
it, as well as things like the
还有一些东西比如说 标题栏
content that's scrolled
模糊了后面
underneath.
滚动的内容
NSVisualEffectView also enables
NSVisualEffectView
the vibrant foreground blending,
还可以使前景能够动态混合
that Raymond talked about, by
Raymond 刚才说过这一点了
taking a grayscale color plus a
一个灰色系的颜色
Blend Mode and making it really
再加上混合模式
pop on top of these backgrounds.
就可以使它从背景中凸显出来
The advanced Dark Mode talk is
高级深色模式讨论会
going to go into a lot more
将非常详细地介绍
detail about how you can use
你可以如何有效使用
those blend modes effectively.
那些混合模式
Turns out that a lot of places
结果是很多地方
automatically get these blur
都自动得到了
materials for free.
模糊素材
For instance, every titlebar of
举个例子 NSWindow 的每个标题栏
an NSWindow will automatically
都会自动
have a titlebar material showing
有一个标题栏素材
onto the content behind it.
显示在它后面的内容上
Source list table views and
资源列表表格视图
sidebar style split-view items
侧边栏风格的分割视图项目
will automatically get a sidebar
会自动得到一个侧边栏素材
material showing onto the
显示在窗口后的内容上
For custom UIs it's pretty easy
对于自定义 UI 来说
to build these custom effects
我们也可以很轻松地
ourselves, as well.
自己设置这些个性化效果
But the most important quality
但是最重要的一点是
of them are the material that
你选择展现哪些素材
We have a few nonsemantic
我们有一些非语义化素材
materials, which, like hardcoded
比如硬编码颜色
colors, just describe the exact
只是显示素材的
visual quality of the material
原本视觉效果
and not the intent of what
而不是你想要展示的
you're trying to represent.
视觉效果
These will not be adjusted for
它们不会自适应
Dark Mode and will stay with
深色模式
that exact quality.
只会一直保持原有视觉效果不变
However, we have a number of
我们还有一些
semantic materials, as well,
语义化素材
which allow you to describe what
它们可以让你描述
type of UI your custom UI is
你想展示的个性化 UI
intending to represent.
是什么类型的
For instance, for a custom menu
比如说对于像自定义菜单
like UI, you would want to use
这样的 UI 你会想要用
the menu material.
菜单素材
And these not only adjust for
这些素材不仅适用于深色模式
Dark Mode, but guarantee that UI
还保证了
to always match those materials
UI 可以一直和这些素材相匹配
even when the system changes in
即便是系统将来
the future.
发生变化
We've had a few of these in the
这些有的之前就有
past, but in Mojave, we have
但是在 Mojave 中
several more so that you can
我们又加了几种新的
make sure to really tailor your
确保真正量身定做
custom UI to match the material
你的个性化 UI
it needs to.
以和它所需要的素材相匹配
Jumping back to our photo here,
回到我们这里的照片上来
we can see that we were using
可以看到我们刚才使用的是
the mediumLight material,
mediumLight 素材
because we were trying to
因为我们想要展现
represent Quick Look style
QuickLook 那样的
popover windows.
弹出式窗口
And instead, we can just simply
我们其实可以直接
swap that over to the popover
使用 popover 素材
material and get the exact
然后得到我们
effect we want to in Dark Mode.
想要在深色模式中得到的效果
Now, this isn't the only area
这并不是 UI 中唯一
where we get a unique material
我们想让独特素材
showing in the background of our
展现在背景中的地方
UI.
我们现在在图集背景中
there's this desktop tinting
展示的就是
effect that's shown here in the
Raymond 刚才说到的
background of our photo gallery.
桌面着色效果
We're getting a little bit of
这里混合了它后面
that blue from that desktop
桌面背景的一点蓝色
behind it, creating this really
制造了一种
visually harmonious result.
视觉上非常和谐的结果
It's a lot easier to see on top
在一个更清晰明亮的背景之上
of a more vibrant background,
比如说这些美丽的花朵图片
such as these beautiful flower
我们就更容易看出来
pictures.
这个效果
There's three different variants
有三种颜色变体
that have semantics with these
和这些背景素材
background materials.
有语义关联
There's the window backgrounds
分别是我们在通用窗口上
that we see on the backgrounds
看到的 “Window Background（窗口背景）”
of generic windows; Under Page
出现在“预览”或 “Keynote 讲演”的
Background, which appears behind
文档后面的
document areas such as in
“Under Page Background
Preview or Keynote.
（页面背景）”
And perhaps most commonly is the
以及可能最普遍的
Content Background material,
“Content Background（内容背景）”素材
which is white in light
在浅色模式下它是白色
appearance and, of course, dark
在深色模式下是深色
In fact, all of these are now
实际上在深色模式下
dark in the dark appearance but
这些现在都是深色
also have that wallpaper tinting
而且带有
effect.
墙纸着色效果
The great news is that it's
好消息是
really not hard to get these
使用这些效果并不难
For the most part, it comes
大部分情况下
completely automatically by
使用系统视图
using system views.
这些效果都是全自动实现的
For instance, the default
举个例子
backgrounds of every window has
每个窗口的默认背景
that window background material
都有内置的窗口背景素材
In addition, [inaudible] views
此外 可滚动的视图
such as NSCollectionView or
比如说 NSCollectionView
NSTableView also automatically
或者 NSTableView
come with the content background
会自动加上
material built right in.
内置的内容背景素材
We've seen a number of places
我们已经看到
across this system that were
整个系统的很多地方
actually able to improve their
其实可以通过
Dark Mode support by deleting an
删除或覆盖这些视图
override of these default colors
带有的多余的默认色
that these views have.
来提升对深色模式的支持
If you want to customize beyond
如果你想在个性化设置时
the default color that these
不使用这些视图带有的默认色
views have, you can explicitly
你可以自己
set a variety of system colors
专门设置一套系统色
as their background color to get
当作它们的背景色
the exact material effect you
以达到你正想要的
want.
素材效果
One really important note here,
但是需要注意的一点是
though, is that if you were to
如果你想要
read the RGB values of these
读取这些颜色的 RGB 值
colors, they would not include
它们并不会包括
the desktop tint.
桌面着色
This is because, as Raymond
这是因为
mentioned, this tint is
就像 Raymond 提到的
extremely dynamic.
桌面着色是非常动态的
As you move your window around
当你在屏幕上
on screen, that's getting
到处移动窗口时
updated asynchronously to the
App 会自动同步变化
applications rendering itself,
自己渲染
creating a really nice
这可以在用户
experience as the user is moving
移动窗口时
around windows.
给他们带来很好的体验
So, jumping back to Chameleon
现在我们回到《Chameleon Wrangler》
Wrangler, we automatically got
我们自动得到了
this content background because
这个内容背景
we just use a stock
因为我们只用了
NSCollectionView.
一个原有的 NSCollectionView
In the vital section, we got
在 “Vital（体征）”部分
that window background material
NSWindow 窗口背景素材
showing through because we had
显示出来了
nothing opaque covering it up.
因为没有什么不透明的东西盖住它
However, in our notes section,
然而在 “Note（笔记）”部分
where we have this awesome
我们得到了这个很棒的
custom stationary, we have a
自定义固定界面
light grey background that isn't
但这个浅灰色的背景
appropriate for Dark Mode and
不适合深色模式
hasn't been adjusted with that
也没有对页面背景语义
under page semantic.
做出调整
We can open up Interface Builder
我们可以打开界面构建器
and see where we're setting up
看一下我们在哪里设置
this background drawing view and
这个背景绘画视图
see that, indeed, we are filing
我们填充的确实是
it with a custom gray color.
自定义灰色
And pretty quickly in IB, we can
在界面构建器中
change that to using the Under
我们可以很快改变它
Page Background color that
通过使用代表那个语义的
represents that semantic and
Under Page Background Color
immediately see that we'll get
我们立刻就能得到
the right result, making it look
想要的结果
just at home with the rest of
看起来和深色模式下的
the document apps in Dark Mode.
其他文档 App 非常一致
The next thing that kind of
然而这里
stands out here, though, is the
比较突出的部分还有
dark foreground on top of light
静止区和文档区
background of our stationary and
浅色背景上的
document area.
深色前景色
And because this is a WYSIWYG
因为这是一个“所见即所得”编辑器
editor where we, as users of
我们作为
Chameleon Wrangler have complete
《Chameleon Wrangler》的用户
control over the colors, images,
对于里面的色彩 图像和字体
and fonts seen within it, we
有绝对的控制权
expect this to stay the same as
我们期望它能和浅色模式下的文档
a light appearing document.
保持一样
However, there are a few subtle
但是这里还有
details that don't seem quite
一些小细节
right.
看起来好像不大对
For instance, the text highlight
比如说 依旧是文档高亮色的
variant of the text highlights,
深色版本
as well as the autocorrect
自动修正气泡
bubbles have the dark
也会自动呈现深色外观
appearance, which really clashes
这就和我们文档的
with the light appearance of our
浅色模式冲突了
We, basically, want to have
基本上我们想要
everything in this area revert
这个区域的所有东西
back to the light appearance,
可以恢复到浅色模式
and we can do that using
我们可以通过
NSAppearance.
NSAppearance 实现
It turns out that NSAppearance
我们发现 NSAppearance
is what's been providing the
正好可以
magic of having light versus
在这个深色模式下
dark variance automatically
提供深色和
switch in Dark Mode this whole
浅色模式之间的
time.
自动切换
You can conceptualize
你可以把 NSAppearance 抽象地理解为
NSAppearance as a little bundle
一小组东西
containing all of the colors,
包含你在整个系统看到的
materials, images, and control
所有的颜色
artwork that you see across the
素材 图像和控件图案
Now, when your application does
现在当你的 App 想要
something like request to draw
做一些类似
with labelColor, what that does
请求改变 labelColor 的事情时
is it looks up in the current
它就会在现有的外观中
appearance for what the exact
查找确切的
RGB values should be.
RGB 值是多少
The same is true for control
处理控件图案
artwork or the different
或者不同的素材效果
material effects.
也是这样
Now, what's new in Mojave is the
我们知道在 Mojave 中
dark appearance, which our
有一个新的深色外观
designers have meticulously
我们的设计者
crafted with redefining
精心设计了这种外观
everything across the system.
并重新定制了整个系统的所有东西
When the system is running in
当系统在深色模式下运行时
Dark Mode, what happens is that
深色外观
the dark appearance gets applied
会应用在你的 App 上
to your application instead of
而不会让 App
the light appearance.
保持浅色外观
So, when labelColor goes to draw
所以当 labelColor 开始绘制时
itself, it references the dark
在深色模式下
appearance as white value
它会参考白色值
instead of the light appearance
而在浅色模式下
as darker value.
它会参考更深的颜色值
The same is true for all of
对于所有的那些素材
those materials.
这都是适用的
And these aren't the only
这些不是系统中
materials in the system.
仅有的素材
Right, these aren't the only
这些也并不是系统中
appearances in the system.
仅有的外观
There are also the high contrast
还有高对比外观
appearances, which get used when
当打开辅助功能
the accessibility high contrast
开启高对比度模式时
setting is turned on, these will
高对比度外观
get applied to your application
就会被应用到
instead.
你的 App 中
And there's actually even more.
实际上还有很多其他的外观
There are the vibrant
有 Vibrancy 外观
appearances that, again,
它可以完全重新设定
colors that appear in sidebars
出现在侧边栏
and titlebars.
和标题栏上的所有颜色
And the advanced Dark Mode talk
高级深色模式讨论会
is going to go into more detail
将进一步介绍
about how you can effectively
你可以如何
use the assets that come out of
有效地使用
those vibrant appearances to
出自 Vibrancy 外观的素材
really make them stand out.
让它们凸显出来
Now, by default, the appearance
现在在默认模式下
of your application will follow
App 的外观会遵循
the system.
系统外观
However, you can explicitly
然而你可以任意
override it by setting the
设置外观属性
appearance property to whatever
来有针对性地
you want.
把它覆盖掉
So, here we have Chameleon
这里有在浅色模式和深色模式下的
Wrangler in Light and Dark Mode,
《Chameleon Wrangler》
and we can see it's following
可以看到现在它们正遵循系统
the system, but as soon as we
但是当我们把外观设置成
set its appearance to always be
一直是 darkAqua
darkAqua, we can see it's always
我们可以看到
getting that dark appearance.
它一直是深色外观
The inverse is true by setting
相反的情况
the explicitly light appearance,
也同样适用于浅色模式
and, of course, setting it back
当然设置回 nil
to nil will have it return back
就会恢复到默认状态
to the default behavior of
和系统保持一致
Now, we know that after a lot of
现在看了那么多 App
you see your apps running in
在深色模式下的运行情况
Dark Mode, you're going to be
你一定很想
really tempted to have your app
尝试让你的 App
always be dark, because it's
一直保持深色
just going to look so good.
因为真的很好看
But like Raymond mentioned, it's
但是正如 Raymond 所说
really important to keep in mind
你要记住
"When it is appropriate to have
什么 App 适合
an always dark app?"
一直处于深色模式
This should be generally
通常来说
reserved for very media focused
以媒体为核心的 App
apps like QuickTime player or
比如 “QuickTime Player”
professional color-sensitive
或者专业的
workflow apps, where it's
对颜色要求很高的工作流 App
important to eliminate all of
这些软件需要去除
the light behind the content.
内容后的所有光线
And, in general, it should be
简单来说
left up to a choice for the
取决于用户自身需求
So, in general, this is the
也就是说
system preference.
这是个系统偏好设置
Some of you maybe already have a
你们中的一些人
dark theme for your application
可能早就通过设置 App 内偏好设置
controlled via app preference,
在 App 中使用了深色主题
so your first step would be to
所以你要做的第一步
tie that back to the system
是要关联系统偏好
preference so the people using
这样在使用系统的时候
the system can have a consistent
也会一直是
experience.
深色模式
And in some ambiguous cases like
在一些模棱两可的情况下
Raymond mentioned, there may be
如 Raymond 刚才提到的
some additional need for an
我们还需要一些附加的
in-app preference, such as in
软件内偏好设置
the mail case, but for the most
比如“邮件”那个例子
part, the system preference
但是大部分情况下
should be exactly what users go
系统偏好应该就是
for.
用户自己的选择
If you do decide you need to
如果你确实确定了
have an always dark application,
你的 App 要一直是深色的
it's really important to not to
记住不要在
use the Vibrant Dark appearance
整个窗口上使用
on the entire window, because
Vibrant Dark 外观
that's not appropriate for the
因为它不适合
opaque window areas of the
App 窗口上的不透明区域
application and are really only
只适用于侧边栏
Instead, you want to use the
如果你想让它
Dark Aqua appearance if you want
一直处于深色状态
to have that always dark look.
就使用 Dark Aqua 外观
In addition to be able to be set
此外 为了
on the window as a whole, you
让整个窗口保持一致
can also set it on an individual
你可以在单独窗口
window or view scoping, and
或者视图范围中进行设置
that's inherited by all of the
这将会被其包含的
views contained within it.
所有视图所继承
For instance, here, we're
比如说这里
setting the sidebar to always
我们设置侧边栏
have the darkAqua appearance if
一直是 darkAqua 外观
we want to experiment with
如果我们想体验一下
something like that.
刚才说的情况
And all of the text and images
里面所有的文本和图像
within that also get that dark
都有了一样的深色风格
styling, but we can also use
我们也可以通过这种方式
this to fix the problem we had
解决之前
before with our text area.
文本区域遇到的问题
We can see here that we actually
我们真正想得到的效果是
want this entire document area
让整个文档区域
to remain having a light
保持浅色外观
appearance, and so by setting
所以通过设置成
the lightAqua appearance, we can
lightAqua 外观
make sure that the text
我们可以确保文本的
highlighting color gets the
高亮颜色
correct appearance as well as
是正确的
the autocorrect bubble
还要保证自动改正气泡
inheriting that light appearance
也继承了浅色的外观
However, in addition to be able
除了可以得到
to be used for some really cool
非常酷的效果
effects, it can also lead to
还可能导致
some hard-to-debug situations.
难以调试的情况
For instance, here, we're using
比如这里的 tableView 中
the vibrantLight appearance
我们用的是
explicitly on our table view,
vibrantLight 外观
and that looks perfectly fine in
在浅色模式下
the light appearance, where it's
看起来很棒
actually already inheriting the
它已经继承了
vibrantLight appearance.
vibrantLight 外观
In Dark Mode, this quickly
但在深色模式下
becomes a very visible problem.
问题就很明显了
We can see that the text and
我们看到表格视图的
images inside that table view
文本和图像
are now inheriting that
同样使用了
vibrantLight appearance and look
vibrantLight 外观
bad on top of that dark
在深色背景上
background.
看起来很糟
So, for the most part, we just
大部分情况下
want to remove these explicit
我们想移除这些
overrides in places where we
特定的覆盖区域
really do not intend to have an
我们不想在这些地方
always light appearance.
一直保持浅色模式
This can also happen in
这种情况同样会发生在
Interface Builder, where, at the
界面构建器中
very bottom of the Attributes
在 “Attributes Inspector（属性检查器）”
Inspector, we've accidentally
的最下方 我们不小心
overridden the appearance for
覆盖了边框视图
our outline view to always be
使它一直处于
the light Aqua appearance.
lightAqua 外观
Here, the fix is simply to
在这里解决方法很简单
change it back to the inherited
只需要把它调回 “Inherited（继承）”
style so that it can make sure
这样就可以确保
to follow Dark Mode when that's
打开的时候是深色模式
turned on, so do be sure to
所有一定要
check for all of those.
检查所有这些地方
At this point, Chameleon
现在《Chameleon Wrangler》
Wrangler's looking really great
在深色模式下
in Dark Mode.
看起来不错
But kind of an understated thing
但是我们还没提到过
here is that, at this point,
到现在为止
we've written 0 lines of code
我们还没有专门为深色模式
specific to Dark Mode.
写过一行代码
The types of changes necessary
要想很好地使用深色模式
for being a great Dark Mode
你需要做出的变化是
citizen is that you need to make
用语义化的方式
sure to express the ideas
来表达想法
semantically rather than
而不是字面上的
So, for instance, these same
比如说
sets of changes allowed our
这一系列的改变
application to not only look
让我们的 App
great in Dark Mode but also in
不仅在深色模式下看起来很棒
the light appearance.
在浅色模式下也不错
Adding support for things like
可以为强调色添加支持
the accent color as well as
还有让我们的标签色
consistent with the rest of the
和系统的其他地方更加一致
Further, these same sets of
并且 这些改变
changes needed to be great in
不仅要适用于
Dark Mode are also the same sets
深色模式
of changes needed to have great
同时还要支持
support for the high contrast
辅助功能设置的
accessibility setting.
高对比模式
So, to reiterate what those
重述一遍
steps were, the first and
这些步骤
foremost was linking on the
第一步是使用 Xcode 10
10.14 SDK using Xcode 10.
关联 10.14 SDK
For a handful of apps that
对于一些
already use system controls and
早就用系统控件和系统色的 App
system colors, this is the only
只需要这一步
and it's already going to look
只需一步就可以使它
great in Dark Mode.
在深色模式下变得好看
For the rest of us, the next
对于其他的
step is to audit our app for the
下一步是审核我们的 App
use of static colors,
看看是否使用静态色
non-template images, and
非模板图像
nonsemantic materials, and
和非语义化的素材
replace those as appropriate.
并把它们替换成合适的
For instance, this might be
比如使用系统色 语义化的素材
material, or, in some cases,
或者在一些情况下
defining a custom asset catalog
在个性化素材目录中
color or image.
定义颜色或者图像
And, again, it's important to
还要再次强调一点
keep an eye out for those
一定要注意有没有
accidental appearance overrides.
意外的外观覆盖
The advanced Dark Mode talk is
高级深色模式讨论会
going to go into a lot more
将进一步介绍更多细节
detail here, including how to
包括如何正确使用 NSAppearance
to do custom drawing and effects
如何在 NSVisualEffectView 中
within NSVisualEffectView, how
做个性化绘制和效果
to make sure all of the myriad
如何确保你在深色模式下
of ways you might be drawing
绘制个性化视图时
custom views work correctly in
每一步都是正确的
Some tips and tricks for using
还有一些关于
View Debugger and Interface
使用视图调试器和界面构建器的建议技巧
Builder to really polish your
可以很好地
app.
帮助你改进软件
And because we know that a lot
我们知道你们中的大部分人
of you and your apps' fans are
和你们 App 的粉丝
really going to be wanting to
想尽快的使用
have Dark Mode as soon as
深色模式
possible, we want to make sure
所以我们想确保
you can do that without
你可以使用这个功能
sacrificing how far you can back
同时不牺牲
deploy.
向后兼容的空间
So, in general, a lot of these
总的来说
features are available for a
这里面的很多特色功能
year or more, but the advanced
都可以使用一年或更久
talk is going to go into details
高级深色模式讨论会
about how to take that even
会更详细地介绍
further back.
如何能使用更长时间
We have a few Cocoa Labs, but I
我们有几个 Cocoa 实验室
also really want to point out
但是我还是想指出
the Dark Mode Lab, where, in
深色模式实验室
addition to engineering support,
除了提供工程支持
Raymond and other members of the
Raymond
design team will be there to
和设计团队的其他成员
help answer any design questions
也会帮忙解答
you might have, as well.
任何设计问题
So, that's a really special
这真的是一个很特殊的机会
treat that I encourage you to
我建议大家去看一看
Thanks for staying until 6:00
谢谢大家一直待到 6 点钟
today, and have a great rest of
希望大家能享受在 WWDC 剩下的时光
[ Applause ]
[ 掌声 ]